Carrie: and this is
Carrie: our first time we try to talk about yinyang and five elements
Carrie: and to be honest
Carrie: : i'm kind of nervous
Carrie: when we decide to do this podcast in English
Carrie: cause as someone who was born and raised in China of course
Carrie: i can speak fluent Chinese
Carrie: but i can not always fully understand what
Carrie: my master Frida says about Yinyang Baozi and five elements
Carrie: but i think this old
Carrie: but mystery Chinese system
Carrie: that can help understand the people's personality
Carrie: and relationships
Carrie: and of course
Carrie: the lift path just based on your birthday and time so
Carrie: i want to introduce my master Freda
Carrie: let Freda help us to go through it okay
ah thank you Karen
i'm not the master
i just try to work out with basic things about Chinese fast
and also the inner element
and to have more people to understand how it works hmm so
Carrie: when we talk about in Yang
Carrie: so um by my understanding of course
Carrie: Yin means negative right
Carrie: Young means positive
Carrie:  and i think most of the western people
Carrie: they already knew  that famous the yinyang picture right
Carrie: so is there anything else you can tell us about the yinyang
frida ah
yes
i think the western people know the yinyang is from the taiji
because we always talk about taiji
if you talk taiji with western people
and then you talk yinyang
they definitely and fully understand um yes
and also i think in western country
actually they use yunyang a lot for example
Carrie: oh really yeah
that's how uh they
they always say a positive thinking or hmm negative thinking
hmm even in Europe i had a friend in Europe in French
and they really really care about what you think
because they truly believe
and what what you think will become the true or reality
so that's why
they always training their kids
or from the little is you always need a politic thinking
so they talk about the energy level
you know the a lot of things
and it it's bit quite it's like
mind game but actually
i think it's not only inside the Chinese traditional system
and um i think in recent four years when we had cover
or even before cover
like for example
hiv test
and they will tell you your test is positive or negative
or even woman pregnant
and they also use a positive negative to definition you have
the have child or not or you pregnant
or not so yeah
so i believe in Yang is everywhere whatever
west country or east country okay
beside this beside the the things you just told us
dCarrie:  do they know the the key
Carrie: concept of the Yinyang
Carrie: i mean the the balance
when when we explain most western people
they understand but they maybe talk a bit different way
but but they they if you talk just simple things for example
you say you say that the in
the biggest inyang in the world is the sun and the moon so
yeah it's bit
like you know the moon will affect the humans black stream
for example um
i i listen a radio is um is talking about the moon um
how the moon affect the the people's um sickness
and um in their record they find um
they had more emergency um usually at full moonlight oh yeah
so so so
that means you know something happened is not just accident
because they had a collective record
and they find it will be more
you know active
or maybe people more active
uh during the full mood more full mood day
and then maybe they go out more or they drink
or they doing some some exciting thing
or they cause their some some problem
or they than in the emergency so so
it's for some reason but if you explain it
they actually they quite accept and understand oh interesting
Carrie: interesting so that means not just i mean the eastern people
Carrie: but western people
Carrie:  people know the Yinyang affect our daily life right
yes but not really detail for example
in in in China
we will separate like for example
the quite is in and the moon is young
and the correct you know like is is is uh
you know it's uh
oxide you know the that that will know
uh also separate or the the moon sound of course
our reset or the shuttle we shut the door
we we call it in or we open the door
it's called uh the the young or like for example
like dark uh bright uh it yeah
it's bit like oxide words
even like you know the going down or going up or something hmm
um but that that not uh to to separate the detail
but uh in traditional uh Chinese we talk about India
that was separate
very detail you know
uh so that's that's a bit different yeah okay
Carrie: so let's try to sort of understand it on a deeper level
Carrie:  from our our show right podcast
Carrie:  so next concept what do you think
Carrie: we should to talk about baazi or all the five elements
Carrie: which one is better i think is uh the purpose uh we learn that
or we
um try to explain is try to let people to uh understand how bad
uh what is bad and how it working um so uh
so all the other element is based on this buzz
so we can just general talk about what is buzz
first
okay
Carrie: so haha i only yeah i have heard about buzz  this word
Carrie: okay
Carrie: uh for a long time but actually before i i met freda
Carrie: i only know maybe it's about the birthday
Carrie: the birthday and
Carrie: and people can know
Carrie: their destiny about their  buzz
Carrie: and actually not really even although not really even know what
Carrie: the path forward at least the people can know
Carrie: and what personality from the the buzz
Carrie: so this is basically all the thing i knew before i met frida
Carrie: but actually i didn't know how
yeah yeah
i can explain that uh actually
bazh has another name is for the uh four pillars of destiny
and we also call uh call it eastern country
uh horoscope because uh that word western people
uh can more easily to understand yeah
and each of the pillows is made up of two
charities it's heavenly stem and an earth branch
so it's repeating the way to the year pillar
month pillar day pillar
and our pillar but actually
in charge in Chi China
the traditional history and when we count the days
we always use a heavenly system
and earthly branch to count every day
so that's why we had the name
we call check your Huang li ah the yeah
the yellow color yeah
Carrie: so what means the Huangli for us
Carrie: if we check it oh
the funny is is about um that day and that time but for example
um um that that day could be you know the head year for example
this year is the dragon year is the wood dragon year
so then they had special months for example
now we are in November so that's called pig months so um
but but that the um heavenly stem
we have to check you know some special way
to get that but in Huang li you can clear see
they are already right there so what
what is that heavenly stem
or you know the earth branch
and they also had the day so for example
maybe uh today is uh
uh like yesterday
uh yesterday is uh
uh i think it's dry them um
um Dragon day i think today is a Snake day
and and for me is usually
if i meet snake day usually
things will happen maybe you have to delay
but actually
we it happened today i got a first forecast before this one
and because we had new people to to organize
so we had delayed few for few minutes and so so so
it's yeah it's quite interesting so they also had a time
special time for example
when you check the Huang li and that time is like now
is nearly two o'clock and so uh
so actually it's called uh
the gold tan so so so
that's why so when you check the Huang li so you will exactly
you will get this
uh so this full pillar
so so you will know
is today is suitable to go out or suitable to doing things
sometimes the day is no good
so it's not suitable to doing something uh for good
or uh for example
if you had shops
you need open then maybe
if the day is not suitable for doing that
so that that's the people check
so
it's bit like you check every day's bus so it's different as uh
it's extremely philosophy for uh for you born in um
the which year
which month which day
and which what was time so
it's the same philosophy
so uh for for the whole universe things
everything that has there but for example
if you you made something you
you made a cup or you made a clothes
and and the time you made it
it's the birthday of this clothes so so
they also had their story yeah
and i think in western country
a lot of people that had packs for example
they had a dog chick maybe uh yeah
cat or chicken or something so so
each animal um
when the time they born
they had their specific the special bus yeah yeah
so that's why we call the yellow Canada
and to check what what bus is so
can i understand that
if people want to know today is lucky or not for you
you have you have to know at least
you have to know your own buds right before yeah
that's okay yeah yeah
because the day for example
we only talk about this day for the one today
that day had the special bags
and maybe it's not suitable for doing something
or you maybe more easy have outside
have an accident or something so so
you can choose like oh is that today
i need to go out uh
know uh drive too much or something so so
that's the key to uh
it's just this day tell you but for personally you had your own
you know the bus but you own fast maybe for this day is okay
but for some people maybe not okay
so that's why we also can choose like even this day is no good
but it's not affect you so much and you still can doing things
but for some people
it affect them so
maybe they cannot they they they doing the things
but it's not a happy ending yeah
Carrie: we have talked about it before
Carrie: because one day when i talked with Freda
Carrie: i told her that i always was on uncomfortable in the August
Carrie: and of course
Carrie: freedom knows my buzz
Carrie: so she said
Carrie: oh maybe it's too much gold in August not good for you right
remember we call mental mental hmm
Carrie: oh okay so
Carrie: because i made this mistake
Carrie: I usde another word gold to say the mental in the wuxing
Carrie: so i think it's a good time to let Freda
Carrie: tell us about WuXing right
Carrie: Is it a good time
oh yes yes uh so um
yeah i think the the wuxing for carry you also know know bit
do you know what the five element yeah
Carrie: of course of course
Carrie: at least haha
Carrie: at least i know what five element and because uh i did made
Carrie: a mistake
Carrie: mistake about the direction we see there's a famous
Carrie: wuxin picture
Carrie: and so freda told me that you'd better remember the five elements
Carrie: from the wood right
Carrie: so the five elements wood
Carrie: fire
Carrie: and soil and no gold is a metal
Carrie: right metle
Carrie: and the water these five
hmm that's five yeah yeah
so and
and just five elements that had the relationship like uh
assist each other for example um
the the wood will assist fire
and fire will assist the soil
and soil will assist mental
and mental will assist water
and water will assist wood
it also had another relationship what does that
Carrie:  it's totally opposite right
yeah yeah
of course hahaha
Carrie: it's from the water
Carrie: from water to uh mandal
Carrie: to the soil to the fire
Carrie: to the wood right
yeah yeah yeah
but it also has relationship for example
they call the conflict
oh yeah
it's bit like control like some ah yeah yeah yeah
Carrie: you mean the ristraction
which which one
Carrie: which one we'd better to remember firstly is from metal oh
yeah you can use oh
yeah
Carrie: okay so the metal restract could i use a restract oh
Carrie: okay the metal restrict wood wood restrict the soil
Carrie: soil restrict the water
Carrie: water restrict fire
and of course
Carrie: fire restrict the mental yeah
that's all good
very good yeah
ha ha thank you
that's a five uh relationship so um
so that's the beginning of
that so hmm so now
i can explain a little bit the five element and so first
we talk about the wood so
i think in in this earth
and wood is the most um plant things uh
in the world so you can go on morning you can see the grass
you can you can see the tree
see the flower you know
that everything is had you know the the green light
and it's for the wood so so for wood
they also um had like uh uh but but before uh
i i explained the wood um uh
i need uh
you know the uh talk about you know the the from the inyang
that had um
major full change
so the full change is called warm the basic thing
we we are in our daily life or a full season
we call a warm
hot cool and cold so oh yeah
that's where the five element comes from it's from the basic
it's from the four season or the four direction so for wood
of course we will think it's spring
it's east and also for wood wood had the
it's you know the special
you know the the the point is the wood will be extend you know
like if you plan something
and they had only had two leaves come
come from the beginning
then they had maybe four or five you know
that they just can't expand you know they had a lot
Carrie: become thrive yeah yeah
and they also had a vibrate so it's it looks like it's alive
you know
it's especially if you planning some veggie
Carrie: means the hope yeah
yeah yeah
you you will see the color and it will bring you say oh
it's growing no
it's happy no
the color is so so that means if the color is good
and then you look it's bright and so you think oh
that one your your plant is grow very well
so so it will give you this this feeling like you know
people keep going up it's also same like a human we have a hope
we always have a hope yeah
uh like Donald Trump and he will say oh
make uh America great again yeah yeah
Carrie: the optimism
so that's all all the the hope yeah and also had like um
uh something like positive uh
we had positive to doing things or positive to grow up
uh like your your uh
everyone want your kids is positive not negative yeah yeah
Carrie: of course
the negative that definitely will bring the problem for you
but if if the positive maybe
they're more willing to help you doing things you know eh
eh you know
make make you feel good yeah
so so that's the one so so
usually is the wood is is the element is like that
but also
we need understand you know for wood we talk about spring so
actually spring
you you feel is like a heart bit warm coming
but it still had a little bit chill of course
yeah yeah yeah so so in inside the bath
we also had temperature temperature means for example
uh your bath if you uh had lots of uh element you know
it's more uh connect with the spring wound so you
you looks a bit warm
but actually had a little bit chill hmm
it's better like for personality you know
uh this person uh is a nice person
but sometimes maybe had a little bit chilly or little you know
yeah
so it was showing your outside yeah but also for the temperature
they also compact with the money for example you got this
element node
uh at the fall pala and uh if if it's a bit warm and towards hot
and usually
we can say oh probably this person is quite rich you know
it is connect for the nature
because you know when we grow things usually
we grow at spring
but we will have lots of lots of results
or you know the the good stuff coming for example
you plan watermelon
then at the summertime you got lots of watermelon coming
hmm so so that's why when the people's uh
you know the the fall pala and they
they bit showing you a bit warm or hot
and actually
they were more close to uh rich but if you like winter time so
it's too cold and you know it's frozen and too many cold
nose warm and cheek maybe the life is bit
a bit tough you know for for some some showing yeah yeah
a tough day right no
that's the that's the wood
then we go forward for the fire so fire yeah
i think everyone knows the fire yeah
fire yeah
because yeah yeah
Carrie: when we talk about oh
Carrie: some boys
Carrie:the boy is hot right
Carrie:so that means yeah another image in this fire huh yeah
yeah yeah
so like we will say when people angry so
so that means you inside your body
the Chi and the fire you know
the gas click then
then you start showing you know that your energy you know
you express out is a bit angry or something you know that
that's also uh
it's it's the fire so
if we just imagine if both people have this this strong feeling
so they definitely will we had a big fighting
Carrie: yeah yeah
and do you know just yesterday and
our farm had one
you know the person to move in for the conven
and he he told us the horrible story so
before he moved to the Conway he lived in the Conway park
you know that he lived in a you know the the camp
and and that night at the middle night
i think around two o'clock and a woman use a hammer to kill a
man oh
yeah so so that must be extremely fair you know
maybe the people drink alcohol
maybe they take drugs and so when they you know they
they couldn't control themselves
and then destroyed so it be the be the like the the fire
the power you know
that will have the uh sublimation of power you know
the power goes up
and they maybe had glories and heat power you know
um so but if if you know everything is goes over
and they will destroy something yeah so
so that's the story a very sad story
but it's also qualified story yeah so
that can explain you know the people you know
too many fire
and that maybe that they were doing something unbelievable yeah
Carrie:so every element have a two side right fire of course
Carrie:means that enthusiasm but another side is can destroy right yeah
if you go to over the limit
you know when in Chinese philosophy
so everything is not enough not enough still okay
because you still can go to reach another level
but if you over the over
once you're over
you can't go back
Carrie:fail so
that's why we always talk about the balance of the element hmm
because if once you're over the limit
and that will step to the destroyer whatever
any element so you can't be over
so once you're over
it's destroyed yeah
Carrie: that's very important okay
yeah yeah
yeah so that's why
so oh because
the the summer uh not only had fire and fire also brings joy
joy hmm uh
so probably you will feel like you know some people uh
born in summertime or something
and maybe
they are personality is more hurry up and more bit tough
and you know you will have a feeling of the joy
you know the the the the the feeling of that so hmm
um yeah that
maybe there's something they a bit careless
just to rush or something so that that could be portable
you know it's it's
it's like you know
some people got too many fire in their you know the uh
what's called the the the bascalla
hmm yeah so that's um
then we go to the next is for the earth soil yeah
that we can say soil
some uh yeah because in the in the universe
the the biggest
soil is earth so hmm so we usually will say when we say soil
we'll talk about the earth but also
the for the soil actually
they had um for they they they carry off the the change season
uh for example uh
if the winter soil when the soil
uh looks when you touch maybe you feel it's cold
but actually inside the soil is a bit warm you know they is bit
like some person you know they looks like they bit cool
or they they not really you know uh you know um for example
they had uh personality is uh
little bit
cooling or something
but you you
when you go with them and you will find they had a little bit
you know comfortable heart in a way you mean ah
Carrie: you remind me that for example
Carrie: a stable stable guy yeah a
Carrie: uh maybe you you can find something some soft areas
right inside right
do you mean that
yeah yeah yeah
something you may be uh
you feeling these people is lonely or fooling
and you know i had one feeling when i was doing my job
and i had one homeless guest
because the government
Australian government actually very good
so they look after the the homeless person
so they give them accommodation you know they
they can live
and
so they also provide you know the people like me to take them
to some place to do the exercise
for example go to the swimming pool
so they had some trainer
they know that
they training them to doing some swimming exercise yeah
so my job is just pick up them and drop them home so that day
um he he did the training for the swimming so after that
he asked me says oh
can we stop at one of my five coffee shop
very close to my house and he want to buy something to eat yeah
so when we go to the shops and and he said oh
he looks a bit happy because usually he give me the
feeling is very cooling or you know the distance right
i said yes and distance with you or something yeah
but that day he looks a bit happy
and look looks so comfortable just feeling comfortable
and then he said okay
can i buy a coffee for you
so i think okay
so he bought a coffee for me with a very you know
the sexful feeling or something you know
like a very good warm or comfortable feeling so
so i still remember he give me handle me
the coffee and he sits there
and he's eat something and drink something
and his face you know
explores some
some some bit warm bright you know
there at that time i feel my heart is bit touched you know um
yeah that imaging is always you know understand yeah yeah
yeah so i just think like you know
even the people had the difficult life or something
and they also still have some you know feeling you know
that that you couldn't you know
forget and yeah
it's from the scripture
but it
it can explain you know that the soil that has different stage
and that has you know the different condition
so that's why we called when we had well underground water
actually winter time you get the water
that water is warm it
because the the surface of the earth is cold
but the inside of the you know the deepest soil
it still had a big
temperature yeah
hmm so so
that's just a get an example to mansion so the the the soil
actually that had a different season you know
that that carry on the change season yeah
Carrie: got it okay yeah
Carrie: then we go to the metal water yeah
oh mando yeah
you always say gold yeah
hmm but um you say gold is is is also correct
is because when we talk about in gold
and most people will connect with gold in in
mental the mental uh
every element we separate in young so
hmm for wood we will say young
wood or in Wu then hmm for the mental also
we had young mental
or in mental so
the in mental is actually is like the gold you know
the hmm is bright
yellow or golden you know
and it's soft you know usually
they cover on the a lot of things outside you know
the surface or the booty you know
they cover with the gold outside
or something so so
that's that's so
the gold is actually is belong to the one major you know
the the mental you know
hmm in this farm element mental yeah
hmm yeah so so
it's also connect with like autumn uh west side and also
it's hard bitter you know like uh
con converging you know
it's bitter like a convergion to get in so so for example
the personality maybe you you can feel you know
some people had a
very strong personality
but you can feel that the heartbeat
um convenging note for when they do things
or talking things or something yeah
so they have their own area you know
this is my my opinion you know it's it's very strong feeling so
if you understand
you can feel like something like that so but also
if extremely you know
they also had a cool of killing you know the the it
it's like you use the the weapon
you know the weapon yeah to to killing something no hmm
it's also the uh connect with the the mental yeah no
that's definitely is the is it in mental right or young mental
um in mental is uh like you know um
some some special year
and then they had a special month you know they had if they had
they had too many in mental um when i talk with my friend
or something and maybe
she was said i don't know what happened but today
i just feeling a little bit sad
you know is this feeling like yeah yeah yeah
you don't know what reason
you just feeling like a little bit sad you know so so
the inventor is give you a little bit of feeling
but not strong not shocking you yes
it's just a little bit eh but the young mental is they
they're going too strong if you will feel big hurt you
you you'll be heard by some you know
whatever some people's words
or if the people's words is very sharp
hmm i just for example for example
when mom you know
and she look after kids
and the kids is not happy to eat the meal
or or every time you know uh
can't you know eat meal
you know the or finish
well yeah
then the mom very angry no
that was them no
no no you know it's a bit like you know like autumn you know
suddenly the temperature is change is cooling yeah
hmm then you can feel the the the change
then you just it's bit like you know someone to hammer you
that is that big feeling so
so people will be you know
the kids definitely will be scared yeah
then we can say punish actually
the punish this word is more connect with the mental
so you gotta punish
because you didn't finish your meal
so you have to go outside and stand at the outside the door
and for maybe five minutes or ten minutes or half an hour yeah
hahaha we we we often see that kind of story yeah so
so that power uh
most of time is belong to the mental power uh
huh yeah so
so for for people
maybe they're doing strongly
you can feel so strong and maybe they
they are born in the day is the young mental day oh
yeah so okay
so the personality is very interesting so you you
you can check your future
if you feeling like yeah something like that
and because i
i did have experience for some some friends
you know that they are young
mental yeah
Carrie: oh really yeah
so i i really understand that yeah
Carrie: so that's a metal maybe one day you can
Carrie: you can just try to help us to deep dive
understand about the thefive elements in YinYang
because i yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah
we we will go through with like uh each heavenly system and so
so we can know you know the the each each element and what's in
what's young what which person is connect with this one
so we can have good example to talk about that yeah
Carrie: to fully understand
so the last one is uh
we we talk about the element is the water
so i think water is we don't need that without water
no one can survive
Carrie: of course
so water is a very big element you know
Carrie: the essential
essential elephant so for the water
water had the personality is like they were running down
you know you know
water can running down
even deep deep
deep under the earth
so that's why someplace we can hide the wheel
and if you check the Australian map for underground water
and you can see
the big map of the area of the Australian underground water so
yeah so
that's that's
the water had for but for example is big maybe
uh you know the people with the water uh
uh you know the element
and uh maybe they will go go down to check like you know
uh the story could be
and this person is is from the the family is very very
you know the the basic family for the uh yes
for the country you know they
they very not good condition or something i
i can explain for like my mom because my mom is water and and
when when she's born that time is
um yeah it's after Japanese war
um and also
yeah it's that time the people's health is not really good
and Medicare system is not good so um
that time women had maybe seven or eight children you know so
when when she family yeah when she's only two years old
her mommy is because he had the the ninth
you know child and then
and when when she give birth to the child
that had a problem so
so she died with the the nice children so hmm
so so
my mom is two years old she lost her mom
and then four years old because the father catch a cold
you know you know
we we will say the cover before so uh
it's like you know people
catch a cold and you could be died or something they of course
lose their lives yeah yeah
actually it's in
the the the long time ago it happened so
that's why so
my mom's father is uh also
i call my grandfather is died when he uh catch a cold
and then because the family condition that time is too poor
so they don't want to pay the money to buy some medicine so
and they didn't realize it's very serious situation so
that's why he loses life so
so that's why
my mom is is a little water
and he is in a very low position
she know like no uh grow up with no father
no mother but he's strongly you know like powerfully
you know to to to grow by herself yeah
so that's why
even now my mom is over eighty
and she's still you know working hard
you know doing things never stop yeah
so so
that's the water water is really powerful for oh yeah
the the water life yeah you know Fred when when you
Carrie: when you talk about
Carrie: the water means keeping running down at that time
i thought oh that means people uh
Carrie: be willing not to fight for but actually
Carrie: it's it's totally wrong
Carrie:  water can also stand for the strong huh yeah yeah
yeah water can stand in the very poor condition
but still strongly to grow up
Carrie: because survive right
survive
because the water harder
the the things is that they can run it down
but when condition change
because you you can see in
the universe the water is always you know up down up
down you know
when heat come
the water goes up
steam you know
it's it's something like that so so
when my mom is when she's young
maybe she had a very poor condition
but when she go to the stage of the fire
and she she moving from the the poor place
and to the big city so so
that's the condition change maybe for some people
is they step on there you know the position
and and straight away go to the very high position
and and the future
we will explain the the person like um a Robert candy yeah
and he is the the the what person as well so so
when we talk about yeah
the the heavenly stamp and we can yeah to to explain you know
know the the more about that so so
we know the the water that had lots of uh things that can change
so that's why for personality
water is is a person they usually like to change so
if you talk with the uh water person
maybe she or he was said oh uh
i like to to change something oh
i want my life to be changed
you know you know
they will have the the the thinking or idea
they want to change it
you know they don't want to stay in the same
same situation or something so so
that's the world we
can you know check you know for the water
because we need to know the water will change their shape
you know they were running down the they
they can hide underground they also can steam in the sky so so
that's why so
water's life is actually is quite
Carrie: interesting
Carrie: not just understand yourself
Carrie: but also understand the people surround you
Carrie: help the people keep a good relationship right
Carrie:  help me to make a good day at least
Carrie: after the the five elements uh
Carrie: which concept do you think we still need to learn
Carrie: if people, our audience want to know what type
Carrie:  their personality like
Carrie: just you said uh somebody is water type somebody is
Carrie: the Wood type right
Carrie: we want to know ourselves with more details
so that's why we have to know so what is heavily uh
the same so for heavenly stem and um and um
i think
the audience can follow us to you know to read these ten first
so um the heavenly stem is uh
so i explain a little bit so
the Jah ja means
Yang Wu
y means Ying Wu and Bing means
Yang fire ding means
Ying fire Wu means
young song g means
Ying song andyoung mentalin mental
young water
in ward so so
that's the ten element actually
we can you know to explain one by one today
so we can use like the example of the person oh
yeah okay yeah so for before we start so we can
have look you know the i made some picture you know first
we talk about the first one we call ja so so what
what what do you think
the the jay do you know the carry
you know anything about that you
Carrie: you mean  just
Carrie: no idea
Carrie:  no idea
Carrie:   is a young wood
right young wood
Carrie: okay young wood
Carrie: wood means the first image is means
um
Carrie: i ll say that
Carrie: of course wood means the hope uh we just talked about it and uh
Carrie: and how do i say that
Carrie: but also i think wood that means
Carrie: not very sharp you know the people not very sharp
Carrie: can just be a good listener  but i
Carrie: can't figure out the difference between the young wood
Carrie: and Yin wood so all the thing i can say is just about wood
yeah so for for talking that
i think we use the famous person to explain uh should be uh
more easy actually
the the people had you know the the we call the the fat
owner is jar and it's anal mask so um
i think every mask everyone know know him
because he is owner of the twitter and now we call
the x yeah so so the the jar um also uh
it's bit like um
we we can't say the the the jar is exactly the wood
it's bit like the seed you know you know
like when we have seed
maybe this seed is tomato
maybe this seed is chili
maybe this seed is is a big tree when when we grow up
you know so so
we don't know what seed is
because you don't know the people grow up
the what environment and what parents they are
and what beseeting in them like hmm
like some i remember is to American president and Obama is
that i have a dream yeah
so it seemed like that i have a dream
so what's the Elon Musk dream
Elon Musk want to move people to the
Carrie: to Mars
Mars yeah
so that that he
he always
he said he he like to know uh change something or something
but he also said like uh he had a period of time
and he feel like uh often better pressure
or disgrace of funding
and uh i can understand
because you just think in the universe the world and actually
the wood when you grow
you take a long time because it's from spring to winter
and you have to face all different challenges for example
today maybe had water or tomorrow maybe too dry
maybe today sun come too hot
maybe maybe the today is no sun at all i
hope i had the sun or something so
that's why the for the wood person
the the personality is very sensitive you know
it's very sensitive with outside environment
or you know the things change or something so
they have to learning like how to you know face the change so so
we can see from the Elon mask story you know actually
he faced lots of you know difficult challenge
difficult situations or money gone you know
things cannot continue and so but for Elon Musk
he had a very famous uh
uh word instead
uh play to win or don't play at all so um
hmm that that sentence is actually
is really much for the uh the the you know jamu and yeah jamu
we called young wood yeah
because uh
because the wood is want doing something and success so so
like if if you you
you just are uh uh like
i said it's a melon or watermelon yeah
you want to be grown up
and then you can start to have the melon
then you can grow up become a big melon
then people happily to eat yeah
so so that's why
so for a young wood
there is a seeding and this seed is will become future
become a success you know
a result to to showing people you know so so
that's why so
we use the aloe mask to explain the Jah so people can uh
more easy to understand so what's
the Jah yeah so then we talk about
d the second uh i love uh
you know the heavenly system so so we use the person um
the uh is um
you know the the also the American the famous um president um
it it's called ah Clinton you know the Clinton
Carrie: yeah of course
yeah the Clinton actually
he is in in wood so in wood is bit like no
the the uh we call young
young wood is is not actually
the the the thing you know the the plan it is
but in wood is actually plan for example
the in wood this one is
the sunflower
or this one is ah know that they're already showing you
you know that they they
they are you know the some
some kind of thing so hmm
so they will have like uh something that
like or don't like you know
they will obviously to showing you
you know uh also you know when when you go to the the universe
you know the the plans or things
and they were uh full of empathy something
so so they their personality will be a bit softer you know
you know that you just think the tree you know
they were waving you know hmm had a bit of softer um
personality uh
but they had strong power inside because you just think you
you are planned
you have to have strong power to inside than you can hold you
know the shape of that yeah so so so
that's why
so people may be showing outside that had some they are no
um kind of you know the
yeah yeah yeah
Carrie: cause everybody knows  mister
Carrie: Clinton is a very charming man right
yeah yeah yeah
that's right yeah yeah yeah
that's why they had the the the love story you know yeah
because he just think the the
maybe he is a flower you know or something
that says got a love story yeah so hahaha yeah
but but for him he said the he said say today
uh future uh belongs to freedom uh not to fear so so
for the the inward actually
they like freedom because uh had freedom
so they can grow
they can flow some you know they can become something you know
they can showing people the the the best part or something so
that's why the the the inward you know they will yeah yeah
totally different type yeah yeah yeah
it's it's a different type of that
but they will show you more soft part you know for something
yeah yeah
no so
that's that's the the second
no the the element uh for the the yeah
for the in in then
we talk about the third you know the heavenly stem we call
the Bing Bing is we call young fire so
yunfai is uh something like
you know the uh sound you know the the biggest
image is a sound yeah
hmm so so for the for the person i um i i use um
i choose the is um is uh
Russia uh president uh
huh yeah so Carol do you know
who is a Russia president
Carrie: Putin
yeah so so pudding uh do you remember uh before
is that before
uh twenty twenty or twenty sixteen or something
hmm more than the Trump
because American president and putting had a very good time
and you know in a all
the Chinese medium you know
they talked about how brave
how bright you know it's like you know a superman yeah yeah yeah
yeah
Carrie: i think it's a image of the alpha man actually
Carrie:  people said
Elon Musk is alpha man right
some some media said that before
Carrie: but actually when you talk
Carrie:  Putin, from the image he is already there right
Carrie: he is alpha man yeah
he he won't be
but he had a problem is he is a fat fat
owner of the young the beam the the fire
but he had the the we called the garden you know
the the garden soil
on the the heavenly stem
so it's bit like you are sun
but but they had a cloud to to block you hahaha
hmm so so so that's why he he tried to be you know um
you know the the the bit famous or
something and always has something to block him
hmm so so
that's why he he can't be shining all the time yeah
he won't be shining shining you know
hmm the world you know you know
like may or something or you know
i had power you know
i had strong hot power
but the thing is because he had a cloud on the coverly color so
that's that means his son is a bit cloud to cover so
that's why he can't be shining you know a lot
so only special special time and it could be happened yeah yeah
interesting so that's why pudding had
the talk is say
say not let the sun look down and say iglorious here
he lies yeah
so it's bit like you know because the sun is a little bit high
yeah so so
so that's why
he when he talk this
i i think that that sentence is more bit
much you know and heat element
hmm so so i use this one yeah
hmm that's good ah yeah
so then we move to the next one
we call the the the fourth uh heavenly system
it's called the thing
hm it means in fire
so the in fire is more
like a candle fire you know
the the the candle fire is more or little and weak right torch
fire you know
the torch yeah torch light you know
the that the in in fire is a very small shining
you know the the the the light something something like that
so so the the story for uh for this person uh
from the the ukin and uh uh
what what's his English name i just bit
uh uhyeah
okay so so
he is the person is is in fire hmm
so we can see you know
when when the Russia had the war with Ukraine
and actually he used his mind you know
the the the little light is also like you know
the people thinking you know
for example some people had a lot of idea
and they can you know this idea and make it working
you know we we can see him to coming here coming there say this
say that and his idea is making you know
the the the the the the lots of country
or things to help him to protect
you know the the Ukraine
you know to help him to protect his country or something yeah
Carrie: just a small flame
yeah it's like flame
and he will come in maybe a once then second and then no
it's hahaha continually
no continually
yeah i think is that already happened four years
or or three years at least four years
i think yeah i think yes
four years already so the war you know you know so so
he's becoming out of this shine the one second
you know it's continually you know uh hmm yeah for his so so
he says he said life will conquer death
light will conquer darkness glory to Ukraine so so this
this talking for him is actually quite much the the infile
because you just use the light
you know to to conclude the the darkness yeah hmm
interesting yeah so
that's interesting yeah so
that's that's what
i think so he is yeah with the like that yeah so so
that's why so the in in fire is is the fire is a bit small
a little light
and it's not uh
not a hundred percent sure and you know sometimes come
sometimes um yeah
it's it's hard or something so so sometimes maybe very quiet
sometimes you know come out you know the so they they
they are the move movement is you know um yes
it's better like that yeah
uh huh so
then we move forward to the the fifth
to the we go to the middle to the fifth of heavenly
then so we call the the Wu to Wu to means the um the young soil
young soil yeah so
the young soil yeah so
the young soil and uh at at the moment think is uh
you know the the Donald Trump choose the uh vice
uh president hmm shady ones yeah yes
Benz yeah so so
Benz actually
he is the the the young soil yeah so so uh
i think he he decide uh when he's had speech
he always talk about his homeland yeah so
motherland
because he's come from uh the small town and yeah so so
he's bringing you know his small town with him
you know the memory
the things and you know
so so he is very care about you know
you know the the place he lived and the people there
and he he care about you know
the what's called specific land for class
or something yeah so
he said is what's more terrible than perverting
is the loss of hope so when you when you live in a land
it's very important
is people you know live with hope so
if if people lost hope in a in a small place or land
and it will be you know
it's very tough or difficult for for the people that live there
yeah because they
they had a limited person they had a small place
and maybe they had you know
limited you know the the source for for living
or something hmm so so so
that's why so um yeah
and also for the for his face or something
and can you feel a bit
like the the the soil feeling like you know
some people had the face
some people like him
because they feel he can be trust do you have this yeah
Carrie: you want to hug them h
because because the soil has this this uh you
know the is it good like you have trust no you know yeah
i'm here i'm there you know
i understand you know
i just stay there and i just hold them there so so
it's bit like a personal you know
personality it's better hmm give people feeling like oh
these people looks like can be trust yeah
hmm yes
and also very stable the interview is very stable hmm yeah yeah
Carrie: of course
that's why they they
Donald Trump even warned him become the marga uh leader yeah
yeah
Carrie: you already talking about Donald Trump
of course four on the jelly ones yeah
so the next one is the dumachump the dumachump actually
also are soil but he is in soil in
soil is fit like you know the garden soil
for example we we have to grow vegetable so so
we had the soil is very rich sauce
or what's called the
what's called what it's called
element something you know the mental element inside
so you can have a lot of nutrition uh inside yeah
yeah so so that's that's called insoil so
hmm so
insoil is is bit
like you can you know the insoil important is you need sun
you need wood so we have looked the Donald Trump one
because Donald Trump is born in the sun you know
the the sun heavily
you know the the stem yeah
so he's born in the young fire yeah
so so that's why
he had a son so you just think if we had a garden garden
big garden yeah
then we had the sun shining on me yeah
and we also had wood
because he born in the the the month is
the young wood you know the the the month
so the the the the heavenly system is is called jiamu is
the young wood so yeah
so this soil actually
they had a wood they had a sun
so that's why he can grow things
you just think he can grow big family
he can grow you know the country
he want you know do is without you know yeah
and he also you know for the garden soil actually
we have to use the hammer you know to dig dig dig dig dig yeah
then then to move move
you may use a machine to go again that put more things
and then you know know so so
he will face you know the lots of like uh difficult situation
but for him
the garden soil is fine because garden soil is naturally they
they can you know solve the difficulty so haha yeah
because that's their nature you know that
maybe they grow up with like that
so you have to solve the problem you know you
you have to face people step on you you know you know yeah
give you you know what yeah yeah
frida actually
i'm curious about um can they can they work
together uh well
because we know
you just said um jelly ones is a is a yangsuoy right you heard
he is a wutu okay and Donald Trump is is in soil
and because he is g to okay and he also said of course
so can help the the the wood to grow up better but can
young soil and in soil work with each other
can they work better they
they can support
support is means like for example
if you are would and another person is
a would so you beat like a brother and sister so so
if if you had this power
it means like you had some people behind you to support you so
it's like a back form you know no
especially the the young soil is more like a mountain you know
it's like a strong mountain stand there
so i'm here and i hold you or something you
you doing something and hold for you so so yeah
so it it we can say support but but yeah
but we always say everything had positive or negative so we
we just say the positive part yeah
it could be the backbone and the the strong support
and we can see for this election and actually
he is the young very strong support even some people think
maybe Vince is a good future
president person you know
maybe because he's young you know he he
he showing people and people feeling like i
can trust this person and yeah
so some people say that
all advances could possible future to be a present yeah
yeah be present
yeah yeah
so so that's why
i think definitely they are good groups to support each other
yeah
Carrie:  interesting, because now it is Donald Trump's administration
Carrie: so everybody kind of expect what will be happening
yeah yeah
so from that so we need to talk about the Donald trump's uh
ex uh was called vice president um actually
he is uh young mental so so
he is gan gan means uh
the fact owner is young mental so uh
his name is pens yeah
it's a token hmm yeah
and and so so this is like you know the the hammer you know
that you know
when you dig the the the soil you know
hmm heavily use hammer give a hit yeah
hmm so so do you feel
when 2020 who give Donald Trump a big hit
of course the person you just you just said yeah
the vice president yeah
because that time everyone is shocking you see in my memory
it's like that so actually
you did give Donald Trump a big hit yeah
but but Donald Trump is still you know can out of this heat
because he is garden soil so even you you dig me you know
i can i can remake it
something like that yeah
so for the for the pens and the
viser present
and he had he said
uh humans see the persons and haven't see the long last future
so so for the mental um yeah
so it's a bit like you know um
the person had you know
hold very strong personality
and they usually
will have you know the view of the the the long future
so for what what
so i don't know but for for him standing
i don't know
maybe he had his view of the long future for something
because
the people will separate with the left hand or right hand
you know if you are really a left hand made you
your view for your long future
then you decide you know to to to choose make your decision
and so it it could be possible yeah
but we just know the the the element of the young gun is
the example is
the is the five percent percent yeah
hmm so punce is
punce is what's a young
Carrie: Young metal
right young mental yeah
hmm wow okay
then we move to the the the carry always say the gold yeah
the the the gold the in you know the we call xing
we call xing jing that means in mental so the in mental
the person is Donald Trump's daughter
ivanka i think it is ivanka is a
Carrie: people said that Ivanka betrayed yeah
Carrie: people say Ivanka betrayed her father but actually
Carrie: i don't know but how do you
Carrie: think about it
i think she's always you know
um give people feeling is looks very good yeah
it's um yeah it's it's beauty you know
um like a tech photo you know she always had actually
i i meet a lot of people on the even on the internet
you know they
they are in mental
they had a bit same thing they really like tech photo
you know you know
like for me
i'm not really like tech photo because i always say oh no
no no this photo looks good this man
but but for in mental
they don't care
they just today take a photo accent to me they take a photo
you know they happily to showing themselves so so
actually inside they they quite happy with themselves like
i just this you know
show you this yeah
Carrie: actually
Carrie: i know several ones like you said haha
Carrie: and they are all ladies oh
really yeah yeah
so so she is yeah like that
so so she said the price of anything is the life you pay for it
but actually
the the in mental is also more connected with the money you know
it's a bit like a gold like you
said it's gold so so
so so they really know
you know the the the price of things you know the um yeah
you have to pay for it so um
for example if the person had the element is a lot
of like the the in mental and actually
they want to be higher level higher level
they want to be their life you know
be looks good you know actually
good yeah and yeah so they like this feeling you know
the feeling like you you wear good
good clothes you eat good things you know
you look pretty and but of course
i don't like cooking hahaha they don't like cooking yeah
because because for men
they just want you know people serves you
and it's really difficult if you had a before men
that had wise is in mental
and they not really like to actually cooking so
because they don't like fire
the fire it comes they don't like it just not really you know
enjoy for that yeah
so that's why they definitely they be rich
and they had someone you know cooking for them
or something yeah so
so it could be yeah
Carrie: can i say  the metal type people
Carrie:  sort of
Carrie: the doing the things on purpose strongly of course
Carrie:  everybody's behavior has their own purpose
Carrie: but they more strongly right
because they more care about their fame hmm
you know
the the the people uh see how the people see them right
how the people feel them oh
so that's why
they pretend you know that that that pride you know that good
in looking hmm you know yeah yeah
yeah so that will had
this kind of strong feel that's why they work the the the if you
your your element has more in you know
the the mental you more likely to step up for example
some people do business maybe they sold gold
or something you know
hmm the the expensive things yeah
something like that it's quite often happened yeah
so people will more like you know
the the expensive things you know to display
you know that looks nice or where a lot of you know
these kind of things you know
make you look
look better or something yeah
so they really care about that
so they really want to go up and something yeah
so for the famous
some famous even China
the famous actor or something and like Fang
bingbing or something hmm yeah yeah
yeah yeah
the in mental quite a lot yeah yeah
hmm yeah so that power is question that's why they want you know
in the public
they want the people look at them oh
you look like gold
Carrie: they want to be the center
Carrie: right the center
so that's the one
hmm then we move on the last two
and hmm so so the the second last
we call the uh young water
we call
young water
so so Carrie what do you think the young water could be
what kind of water
you think is young water
you just talk about your mom is a water
type so
Carrie: of course i know the water type that means can
Carrie: they have survivability
Carrie: and they can change when the situation changes
for example some water is drip water my mom is drip water
drip water drip water
just a little bit
i see yeah
but some water is very big huge
so do you think
what kind of water is big and huge
Carrie: but you know water people
Carrie: when people think about waters
can help us allot but actually
Carrie: when the water become the animal
Carrie: i mean
Carrie: but it's also horrified right
Carrie: it's in Japanese, KOWAI
yeah yeah yeah
Carrie: because everyone knows what happened in Japan about tsunami
right yeah yeah
so it's just sea so
it's just coming like a sea you know so
so the very important person
we today we talk about this is Steven bano
uh huh Steven bano is young water
wow so
so you just think uh huh
what's Steven Ben knows a medium called warroom yeah yeah
they think the warroom is like for waterman hahaha yeah
and in China we also call the jianghu
jiangfu is the the young world is like jiangfu
you know you know running
you're running from here to there you know running everywhere
you know you you
you you look up this whole world you know
it's yeah so you
you have the heart very openly you know
it's you know it's big and something like that yeah so
yeah so
Steven Benon said a good judge of Thailand
may the Trump president
yeah
i see young young
you know the the the young water that had a big goal
it's like you know the we can see the sea they will know uh
in China we call the uh
dajiang dongqi means the water will running running
running to the east yeah
hmm yeah
so so probably yeah
i think that yeah
so for for him definitely had big water
because we can see he's born in the water yeah
and he's born in the water months and he's born in the water day
oh so so in his element he got four water hmm yeah
we just think we only uh
the bus only had eight you know the eight
hmm eight uh
the the heaven earth you know the friend
and and he had the full half is water
it means pure water right
yeah so you just think how big the water is
and he also he had inward and young water
but he's uh the the you know the the fat owner is young water so
that's why so
we understand yeah
so so how he is
and so we we
we can understand
why he want doing the big thing
he want to join the you know the the the little water
and become the the big water so
it's just like uh
he always says what ayeah
yeah he care about
Carrie: average people
in every individual
whatever this person is poor or you know the situation
or in which country
or something he care about you know the yeah each job yeah yeah
something right
and he wanted to keep the the whole job together like he
he organized a margar yeah
hmm it's something like the people you know he
he makes the people together what they do they
they want Donald Trump
make Trump president
that's his goal yeah
big goal yeah yeah
so that that's his young world story now now
i understand okay so
Carrie: who is the last one who
is the last one
Carrie: really okay
you mean in water
Carrie: Freda sorry Yin water means is drip water yeah
in water is drip water okay yeah
for example like in the morning you go outside
you see on the grass that has a little little
you know the shining water
hmm that's all called in water
i see water you should like put them like a rain
know the rain coming a little drip little drip
that's also part of the in water yeah
hmm so so
in water
is you have to combine with this one that one you know the
and and they will change they are sharing you know up down up
down something but depends on what what they mean for example
if they made the fire the definitely what goes up and yeah
and why he is good with
Donald Trump because Donald Trump is the soil but actually
he needs water yeah
you just think Donald Trump
had Stephen Bannon in the water to help him
and had the robbed Candy in the water to help him
and Donald Trump also needed the wood
because if you are so you want the water
and you want the growth in so
so Elon Musk help you so
that's why they are a very great team for Donald Trump yeah
Carrie: Freda made a circle now actually
Carrie: we can connect every point together to understand
Carrie: why we talking about the five elements
Carrie: and the Bazi right now
yeah so so
that's why i saw the ah yeah
the the the Robert committee and you when when you see
he's talking so what do you want to do
he want to change
he want to change things
he want to change medical system he want to change
you know the the world organization
you want to change lots of things yeah
so he want American be healthy again
because you just think drip water the harder
the uh the type is they can save life
without water
nothing can survive so water has important you know the source
right they want to save the life they happily to see
you know the life things for the like my mom yeah
she happily see what a duckling baby
you know everything is alive
and she is happy to see and to help yeah so
so for for him is the same you know he he
he sees the the American children suffer
he see lots of people suffer
and he want to save this person he want to give them you know
the support to change them you know
it's it's something like that so so
that's why so
he say the world is indeed full of suffering
hmm sorrow ignorance and violence
but hmm never feel depressed
because you think there is nothing you can do about it
so that's why
he thinks i can do something about it
because you lost hope and of course
you do nothing
yeah yeah so
so i think so yeah
that's today's yeah
Carrie: at the end of our first episode actually
Carrie: the last minute the last thoughts
Carrie: so i don't need to remind Freda
Carrie: Greda already gave us the
Carrie: the reason why we want to do this podcast right
Carrie: actually yeah
Carrie: she already told us and actually
Carrie: we also want uh the the people can give us more comments
Carrie: more feedback
Carrie: let's uh communicate
Carrie:  i don't think
Carrie: there's a huge uh
Carrie: gap between the eastern people and western people
Carrie: i think we can talk with each other
Carrie: once uh we know what uh want to do right
Carrie: we are an optimistic people
Carrie: so we can work together what do you think
freda yes yeah
i'm so happy to to talk about this topic
and yeah so
because we also hope the world were getting better you know
people would not stop suffering and something yeah
so i think the first thing we understand ourselves
and we understand other people and yeah
then we know how to yes
to communicate with other people and to be better positive
and yeah
so that's when we call the life change yeah okay
Carrie: let's see next time okay
okay thank you hmm
thank you time Carrie see you